<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Engine</title><link>https://snarr.github.io/Engine/</link><description>Recent content on Engine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 02:19:50 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://snarr.github.io/Engine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Christmas Tree</title><link>https://snarr.github.io/Engine/examples/christmas-tree/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 02:19:50 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://snarr.github.io/Engine/examples/christmas-tree/</guid><description>This program was created to help me develop Image-based Sprite support within the Engine.
Both the background image and the actual Christmas tree itself are drawn from PNG files.
The lights flashing over the tree, however, are drawn using the Canvas API and randomly positioned across the tree using code.</description></item><item><title>Flappy Square</title><link>https://snarr.github.io/Engine/examples/flappy-square/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 02:19:50 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://snarr.github.io/Engine/examples/flappy-square/</guid><description>Based on the popular iOS game &amp;lsquo;Flappy Bird&amp;rsquo; by Dong Nguyen, this program was the first example created to test the game engine. Developing this program alongside the engine helped me explore the initial design of the codebase and key design decisions like:
Would I use JavaScript or TypeScript? Would I use Constructor Functions or Classes? What would be responsible for drawing Sprites, a Canvas object or the Sprite object? The program also forced me to develop new library features like an Input class for keyboard inputs and Collision Detection between Sprites.</description></item><item><title>Game of Life</title><link>https://snarr.github.io/Engine/examples/game-of-life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 02:19:50 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://snarr.github.io/Engine/examples/game-of-life/</guid><description>John Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life cellular automaton programmed using this game engine. I created this example to test the Group class, which allows you to store Sprites inside of an Array-like object.
In the current implementation, the Group class extends Array, giving it all of the normal Array properties and methods.
Sprite properties and methods can also be called on a Group to update all of the items in the Group.</description></item></channel></rss>